Olubunmi Ruth Alao

Shttp://bumsyalao.me/ ■ bumsyalao@gmail.com Chumsyalao 🛅 /bumsyalao 📞 +971501507152

3+ years of experience in web application development, working mostly with JavaScript; React as frontend framework and NodeJS as backend solution. I understand business requirements, prioritise work based on highest business value and work with teams to solve problems.

Relevant Experience

Software Developer (contractor) at IBM

Dec 2018 - Present

Feb 2018 - Dec 2018

I worked on the TAMM Project here In Abu Dhabi. It is an impactful project aiming to revolutionise how citizens of Abu Dhabi interact with government services.

Built highly optimisied frontend visualisation of investement data using charts, graphs, highly interactive investment maps and business calculators for potential business investors.

Managed business processes with camunda business process modeler, while following agile software programming practices. Wrote Frontend and Backend tests.



tamm.abudhabi

Remote & Freelancing

I Worked remotely with engineering teams to build web applications I worked on Stanbic Bank IBM APIC; Deployment of UAT, Test and Production servers

Set up network servers for the API Gateway DB, API manager and Developer portal.

Set up load balancers, to connect with the API cloud and manage network traffic.



Software Developer at Andela NG

Aug 2017 - Feb 2018

EFT Specialist at Interswitch NG

MSSQL

Jan 2016 - Aug 2017

I built Full stack applications using Micro-service for frontend and backend architecture while following agile software programming practices.

Wrote Front-end, Back-end and E2E test.

Contributed to Reaction commerce open source.

Contributed to Cards For Humanity, a fast-paced online version of the popular card game, Cards Against Humanity.



Full FEP Deployment, Upgrades, Maintenance & Support of core banking systems (Postilion, Postcard, Postilion Office).

HSM (Hardware Security Module) Deployment.

Channel Enhancement & Certification (ATM, POS, WEB, and Mobile). Integration to external systems and networks. Examples: Integration to Processors/Switches (MasterCard, VISA, VERVE).

Installing, managing, upgrading and administering Microsoft SQL

interswitch.com

databases

Education

Covenant University

2010 - 2014

Postilion

Bachelor's Degree, Computer Science

CGPA: 4.43/5

Final year project: A Computing Platform for Metabolic Network Visualization and Topological Analysis.

Selected Personal Projects

2019 **The-Consent-Game** Post-It

The consent game is built for The Consent Workshop, to teach young adults about consent.

React Redux SCSS Javascript ES6 Post-it is a simple application that allows users create groups and

post messages to group.

NodeJS SCSS PostgresSQL React Redux Javascript ES6 S post-it

2017 2018 Ideabox **Flames**

Ideabox is a simple application that allows users to create a pool of ideas and promote collaboration.

NodeJS React Redux SCSS Mongoose Javascript ES6 ideabox A game of love and prediction. **♦** Flames HTML CSS Javascript

Selected Awards and Certifications

Front-End Web Developer 2018 **Microsoft Certified Professional**

2016

2017

Microsoft License 13392204

Lean Six Sigma Yellow Belt Certification

Python-codecademy 2017

Codecademy

2017

See certificate

Udacity

2016

Postilion Basic Traning

ACI worldwide